rockport.com 2015-05-31

# Rockport® Shoes | Privacy Policy

## Introduction

The Rockport Company, LLC ("Rockport") respects the privacy of visitors to the Rockport websites. Rockport has adopted this privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") to inform you of what information we collect from you on or through the websites located at the following domain names: www.Rockport.com and help.rockport.com (collectively, the "Websites"), how we collect that information, how we may use it and the steps we take to protect it.

This Privacy Policy applies only to these Websites. Rockport is not responsible for the privacy practices of any company to which our Websites might link. For access to the privacy policies of those sites, please refer to the policies provided by those sites at their home pages.

## Your Consent

Rockport will not collect personal information from you without your express consent. By using the Websites you consent to the Privacy Policy, which governs the collection and use of personal information via the Websites, as well as to our Terms and Conditions.

What kind of information do we collect?

## Personal Information

Rockport collects personal information when you open an account, submit orders or purchase merchandise from the Website, or otherwise provide information to participate in the services and offerings on the Website. On such occasions, the personal information collected by or on behalf of Rockport may include, without limitation: your name, e-mail address, date of birth, billing address, shipping address, zip code, telephone number, mobile phone number, credit card information, debit card and related information, information concerning your interests, and other demographic information, as applicable. We may also ask some additional optional questions to help us better serve you. Please note that when you make a purchase from any of the Websites, we may need to contact you via phone, postal mail or e-mail if we have questions regarding your order.

To customize our response to your preferences with your consent, Rockport may ask you for personal information, such as your name, address, date of birth, gender, e-mail address, telephone number, mobile phone number and similar information. We do this, for instance, when you establish a user profile or account, register for contests and promotions, submit requests to Rockport customer service, respond to communications from Rockport and for other services that require registration or subscription. When you establish a user profile, we may also request optional information from you regarding certain user preferences and similar information. In addition, personal information is collected in certain portions of the Websites in which visitors specifically and knowingly provide such information along with content submissions, community postings (e.g., chat or bulletin boards), suggestions, surveys, polls or voting.

Rockport may also collect personal information from you about a third party to carry out services relating to you or that third party at your request. For instance, you may provide us with personal information about a third party when you request that we ship an order to a third party or to send an e-mail or e-postcard to a third party. That information will only be used for the specific purpose of responding to your request, such as delivering the e-postcard or to process and ship the order and confirm shipment.

## Non-Personal and Aggregate Data

When you visit our Websites, we may collect "click stream" data (IP address, server address, domain name, browser information, and other non-personally identifiable information regarding your visit. This information may be combined with information you have provided to us (for instance by registering), which will enable us to analyze and better customize your visits. Like many websites, we may collect information regarding website usage by using cookies and tracking technologies. We may use information gathered from the cookies and tracking technologies to analyze and understand how the Websites are used and to enhance your visits to the Websites. For example, we may use cookies and tracking technologies to: (i) customize account pages for you; (ii) track user visits and account set-ups; (iii) determine what set-ups are most frequently requested; and (iv) provide for a "remember me" function to save your user name and password so you do not have to provide it each time you visit the Websites. You can find more information on how we use cookies in the section titled "Use of Cookies."

We may also use a third-party service service provider to help us optimize the products and services we offer through the Websites. That third party may place web beacons or data tags on the Websites and/or a cookie on your computer to facilitate collection of information on use of the Websites each time you visit the Website ("Session Data"). If, at any time you do not wish to allow your Session Data to be aggregated and analyzed by that third party, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) and utilize the opt-out mechanism. This opt-out mechanism is only applicable to cookies placed on your computer by that third party.

## Use of Cookies

A "cookie" is a small string of information that the website that you visit transfers to your computer for identification purposes. Cookies can be used to follow your activity on the Websites and that information helps us to understand your preferences and improve your website experience. Cookies are also used to remember user information such as your user name and password.

You can turn off all cookies if you prefer not to receive them. You can also have your computer warn you whenever cookies are being used. For both options you must adjust your browser settings. Please note than when you set your computer to reject cookies, the settings may limit the functionality of the website you visit and it is possible that you will not have access to some of the features on the website.

## Use of Visitors' Information

Except for the purposes set forth below and otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, Rockport will not share, sell, trade or otherwise transfer personal information provided by you on or through the Websites to third parties without informing you in advance. We will primarily use your personal information to provide products and services to you and to perform the following:

**Business Uses** \- Rockport uses the personal information that you provide to: (i) establish user profiles and accounts and store user preferences; (ii) administer and fulfill contests, promotions, surveys or other site features (for instance to deliver a prize you may have won in a contest); (iii) provide you with the products or services that you have ordered or requested; (iv) process and ship orders; (v) send order and shipping confirmations; (vi) provide customer service; (vii) process returns or exchanges; and (viii) protect you, and us, against error and fraud; (ix) keep records of returns and exchanges; and (x) as needed to investigate or enforce legal rights and obligations.

In addition, if you have opted-in to receive communications, including e-mails and/or SMS messages from Rockport. We will use personal information provided by you to customize advertising and content we present to you, and to send you information and materials, including, without limitation, via e-mail or SMS messages about products, offers and news we think could interest you. This information may relate to products, offers and news of Rockport or its licensees or carefully selected commercial partners.

**Third-Parties** \- Information collected on or through the Websites may be shared or transferred to third parties who may be located outside the United States who perform services for us or with whom we contract for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. For example, we may use third parties to host our Websites, assist in designing and operating the Websites or certain features, perform services (e.g., prize fulfillment), print or send communications on behalf of Rockport, authorize and process payments, process and administer gift cards, provide customer service and help us analyze data.

Rockport requires that these third-party providers to employ a comparable level of protection for personal consumer information. Further, Rockport only provides these third-party providers with the personal information necessary to perform their designated functions and services for us. You may be asked on certain areas our Websites whether you wish to receive information from third parties and, upon your consent, Rockport and/or those third parties may use the personal information you provide to contact you consistent with the consent that you provided as permitted by applicable law.

**Affiliated Businesses; Business Transfers** \- We may share the personal information you have provided us among our affiliated businesses that we control or that are under common control with us. They may use this information to offer products and services to you consistent with the purposes identified in this Privacy Policy, to the extent permitted by applicable law. The personal information that we collect may also be transferred as an asset in connection with a merger or sale (including any transfers made as a part of an insolvency or bankruptcy proceeding) involving all or part of Rockport or as part of a corporate reorganization, stock sale or change of control.

**Required Disclosures** \- We may share personal information you provide to us with a third party if we are required by law to disclose that personal information. For example, we may be required to disclose personal information to respond to a subpoena, court order or other legal process, including any administrative proceeding, or in connection with an investigation. We may also disclose this information in response to a law enforcement agency's request or as otherwise required or permitted by law when the information is relevant to investigating a violation of law or to address an emergency that threatens an individual's life, health or security.

**Non-Personal Information** \- We may use non-personal information to analyze visits to the Websites and learn about the interests of our visitors in aggregate and to better understand your interests and needs, so we can improve our products and services and deliver to you the type of content, features and promotions in which you are most interested. We may share non-personal, aggregate data with our marketing partners or other third parties for research and marketing purposes.

We may on occasion combine information we received on or through the Websites with information obtained from other sources and outside records to enable us to update and correct the information contained in our database.

## Who Manages Visitors' Information

The global and local websites of Rockport and the information collected, are managed and controlled by Rockport or by third- party service providers that are required to maintain the security and confidentiality standards described in this Privacy Policy on behalf of Rockport. The servers that make the Websites available and that store the information collected by Rockport are located in the United States of America.

## Protection of Visitors' Information

Rockport takes administrative, technical and physical precautions to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft, and misuse, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction and requires its third-party service providers to do the same.

You can help us by also taking precautions to protect your personal data when you are on the Internet by changing your passwords often, using a combination of letters and numbers, and making sure you use a secure web browser.

## Security Policy

Rockport’s policy regarding the security of credit card information can be found by clicking on the “Security Policy” link on the left hand side of this page.  The Security Policy is incorporated into this Privacy Policy by reference.

## Children's Privacy

For the United States, Canada, Australia, and the European Union only, Rockport does not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13 for marketing purposes, because some information is collected electronically, it can appear to be the personal information of the Rockport purchaser of the product, and will be treated as such by this privacy policy. If a child under 13 submits personal information to Rockport and we learn that that personal information is the information of a child under 13, we will attempt to delete the information as soon as possible.

For Brazil only, Rockport does not knowing collect personal information from children under 16. If a child under age 16 submits personal information to Rockport and we learn that the personal information is the information of a child under 16, we will attempt to delete that information as soon as possible. 

Except as stated above for the specific countries identified, Rockport does not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are under the age of 18 and in a country that prohibits the collection of personal data from persons under the age of 18, you should not provide any personal information to us and you should use the Websites only with the involvement or a parent or guardian.

## Right of Access

You have a right to access your personal information. You may exercise this right by visiting the "My Account" section of the website. From this link, you can view, challenge, modify or delete your personal information from our database. Please note that Rockport reserves the right to retain personal information relating to you reasonably necessary to document its business activities or as needed for required disclosures.

## Choices You Have

No one is required to provide us with personal information. Your provision of any personal information to us on or through our Websites or by other means must be voluntary and with your consent to the uses described in this Privacy Policy. In some cases, only persons who provide the requested personal information will be able to order products and services or otherwise participate in the Websites' activities and offerings.

If you would like to be on our e-mail list, you will be provided with the opportunity to designate your preference on the Website. You will also have the opportunity to "opt-in" to join our mailing list to receive catalogs and related materials through the mail. In addition, if you provide your mobile phone number and would like to receive text messages and/or SMS messages from us, you will have the opportunity to "opt-in" to receive those communications.

## Opt-Outs

If you want to opt-out of having your personal information shared with our affiliates please visit the "My Account" section of the Websites, or send a letter to Rockport at:

Attn: Global E-Commerce  
The Rockport Company  
1895 J.W Foster Blvd.  
Canton, MA 02021

You also will have the opportunity to opt-out of receiving future e-mail communications by clicking on an "unsubscribe" hyperlink contained in promotional, commercial e-mails we send to you.

Please note that unless you cancel your registration, you will not be able to opt-out of receiving all types of communications, such as service announcements and administrative messages, as these types of communications are a necessary part of your account and use of the Websites.

## Cancellation of Registration

You may cancel your user registration at any time, and you can choose to opt-out of receiving any future e-mails and/or SMS messages from Rockport. Please note that modifications of the status of personal information will not stop e-mails and/or SMS messages (i) generated before Rockport can accomplish the modification of the status of personal information or (ii) from third parties with whom Rockport may have already shared that personal information consistent with this Privacy Policy.

## Changes to the Policy

Rockport may update its privacy policy from time to time due to changes in regulations and to keep up with new developments and possibilities on the internet. When we change the policy in a material way a notice will be posted on our website along with the updated privacy policy.  Your continued use of the Websites constitutes your consent to the updated privacy policy.

## European Union and Swiss Residents

If you choose to provide Rockport with your information, you consent to the transfer and storage of that information on our servers located in the United States.

Rockport adheres to the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework Privacy Principles of Notice, Choice, Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity, Access and Enforcement, and is registered with the U.S. Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor Program.

Any questions or concerns regarding the use or disclosure of your information should be directed to Rockport by calling us at **1-800-828-0545** or sending us an email at customercare@help.rockport.com. We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. For complaints that cannot be resolved, we have agreed to participate in the dispute resolution procedures of the American Arbitration Association pursuant to the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Privacy Principles. For clarity, this "European Union and Swiss Residents" section of this Privacy Policy applies only to residents of the EU and Switzerland.

## How You Can Contact Us

If you have any questions, comments or complaints about the site or any of our services, please visit the [Contact Us](http://www.rockport.com/contact/contact-us-details,default,pg.html) section of our web site, or write to us at:

Rockport Attn: E-Commerce  
The Rockport Company  
1895 J.W Foster Blvd.  
Canton, MA 02021
